John Wei Kang ONG

Mobile: +65 8223 5074

Email: weikang.ong@u.nus.edu Skype: ongwk95@hotmail.com



Personal Statement

Internship Objective

Through the internship, I hope to make a positive impact for the company I work for, contributing in any way I possibly can. It will also be a good networking opportunity for me to interact and find like-minded individuals in the startup and software scene. I also hope to deepen knowledge in my specialisation, software engineering by picking up more technical skillsets that the company require.

About Me

I am currently a Year 2 computer engineering student. As an avid programmer, I hope to innovate better technologies to improve people's lives. To reach this aspiration, I participated in various events and hackathon to hone my skillsets. One particularly memorable experience was from the Startup Weekend Singapore Mega Event, hosted by Techstars, where teams turn ideas into startup in 54 hours. My team developed a location-based interest app for users with similar interests to mingle. This was an eye-opening experience for me as I went through the different stages of a startup. I aspire to put the knowledge and skills into a startup aimed at improving people's lives in the future.

Strength

One of my strength is my ability to lead. I can rise and take lead naturally when there is a need, uniting the team towards a common goal. Another one of my strength is my ability in interpersonal communication skills. I can communicate clearly my ideas and thoughts with people of diverse background and build good relationships. Lastly, one of my strength is my ability to be strongly independent. Having served in the military for two years, I was exposed to harsh and hostile elements as part of my resilient training. This has taught me to adapt and adjust quickly to a new environment.

Work Experience

I had recently concluded an internship at Manifera Software Development Pte Ltd. As a software development intern, I led a team of 7 engineers to develop an inventory management system for KK Women's and Children's Hospital. I was also the lead developer for the web based management application which interact with the hardware sensors to provide real-time inventory monitoring. This was an enriching experience because I was given the opportunity to develop the whole concept from ideation to a sustainable business model.

How can I contribute

I am willing to contribute to the company in any way I can. Apart from software development, I am willing to pick up new skillsets the company needs. Given my strong leadership qualities, I will be able to lead a team in a project confidently and can contribute unique ideas and solutions. With a strong set of technical skills, I am excited and confident in learning and contributing in the technical development.

Education

Aug 2016 - Present National University of Singapore

Bachelor of Computing (Honors) in Computer Engineering

(Course details in Appendix A)

Jan 2012 - Dec 2013 Anderson Junior College

• Singapore-Cambridge General Certificate of Education Advanced Level

• Subjects: Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics, Economics

Work Experience

May 2017 – Aug 2017 Manifera Software Development Pte Ltd

Software Development Intern

- Led a team of 7 engineers to develop an inventory management system for KK Women's and Children's Hospital
- Developed a web based management application using MEAN framework
- Integrated hardware sensors and software for a seamless monitoring system

Feb 2014 – Jun 2016 **42nd Battalion, Singapore Armored Regiment**

Section Commander

- Awarded Best Commander for the month of April 2015 for display of dedication and leadership
- Served as an Armor Driving Tester

Scholastic Achievements/Extracurricular Activities

Sep 2017 – Oct 2017 Startup Weekend Mega Singapore Event

• Led a team of 7 participants in conceptualizing an idea into a startup within 54 hours

Developed a location-based interest app prototype

May 2017 – Aug 2017 Orbital Project

 Led a team of 2 as part of a self-directed and independent software development project

Co-developed an Android game app using Unity development

Jan 2017 – Feb 2017 IDEa\$ Challenge Hackathon

• Led a team of 4 freshmen across engineering and business faculties

Developed a seat management system for libraries

Achieved Best Participants Award

Jan 2012 - Dec 2013 Anderson Junior College

College Class Leader Award for recognition of contributions to college activities

 Platinum Social Service Award for contributing more than 300 hours of community service

Skill Sets & Proficiency

Programming Java **Proficient** С **Proficient** C++ Basic C#

Basic

Web **HTML** Intermediate

CSS Intermediate Intermediate **JavaScript** PHP Intermediate Intermediate Node.is Intermediate **iQuery** AngularJS Intermediate **Express Framework** Intermediate

Database Intermediate MongoDB

Integrated Development IntelliJ **Proficient Environment**

Proficient Atom Unity Intermediate Eclipse Intermediate

Proficient

Visual Studio Basic

Server Management & Server Setup/Maintenance Basic Network

Operating Systems Windows XP, 7, 10 **Proficient**

Hardware Design HDL (Verilog) **Proficient**

Arduino prototyping **Proficient** Circuit design Basic

Non-technical Skills **Proficient Project Management**

Language Proficiency

Version Control Tools

Spoken English - fluent; Mandarin - fluent

Git

Written English - competent; Chinese - average

Degree: Bachelor of Computing (Honors) in Computer Engineering

Cumulative Average Point: /5.00

Classification	Course Name	Grades
Software Development	Introduction to Computer Engineering	
	Programming Methodology	
	Data Structures and Algorithms I	
	Discrete Structures	
	Software Engineering	
	Computational Thinking	
	Independent Software Development Project (Orbital)	
Hardware Development	Electrical Engineering	
	Devices & Circuits	
	Real-Time Operating Systems	
	Digital Fundamentals	
Interpersonal Skills	Critical Thinking & Writing	
	Effective Communication for Computing Professionals	
Others	Introduction to Design Thinking	
	Mathematics I	
	Mathematics II	

NUS Grading Scale:

A+ & A (5.0); A- (4.5); B+ (4.0); B (3.5); B- (3.0); C+ (2.5); C (2.0); D+ (1.5); D (1.0); F (0)

S = Satisfactory; U = Unsatisfactory

CS = Completed Satisfactorily; CU = Completed Unsatisfactorily

EXE = Exempted; IC = Incomplete; IP = In Progress; W = Withdrawn